export const quizData = [
  {
    question: "When did World War 2 begin?",
    options: ["1914", "1939", "1945", "1929"],
    answer: "1939",
  },
  {
    question: "Which country was invaded by Germany to start World War 2?",
    options: ["France", "Poland", "Belgium", "Soviet Union"],
    answer: "Poland",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who was the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom during most of World War 2?",
    options: [
      "Winston Churchill",
      "Neville Chamberlain",
      "Clement Attlee",
      "Margaret Thatcher",
    ],
    answer: "Winston Churchill",
  },
  {
    question: "What was the name of the German air force during World War 2?",
    options: ["Wehrmacht", "Luftwaffe", "SS", "Gestapo"],
    answer: "Luftwaffe",
  },
  {
    question: "Which event led the United States to enter World War 2?",
    options: [
      "Invasion of Poland",
      "Battle of Britain",
      "Attack on Pearl Harbor",
      "D-Day",
    ],
    answer: "Attack on Pearl Harbor",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which battle is considered a turning point on the Eastern Front?",
    options: [
      "Battle of Stalingrad",
      "Battle of Berlin",
      "Battle of Kursk",
      "Battle of Moscow",
    ],
    answer: "Battle of Stalingrad",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which two cities were targeted with atomic bombs by the United States?",
    options: [
      "Hiroshima and Nagasaki",
      "Tokyo and Osaka",
      "Kyoto and Hiroshima",
      "Nagasaki and Kyoto",
    ],
    answer: "Hiroshima and Nagasaki",
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the leader of Nazi Germany during World War 2?",
    options: [
      "Adolf Hitler",
      "Joseph Stalin",
      "Benito Mussolini",
      "Charles de Gaulle",
    ],
    answer: "Adolf Hitler",
  },
  {
    question: "What was the codename for the Allied invasion of Normandy?",
    options: [
      "Operation Barbarossa",
      "Operation Market Garden",
      "Operation Overlord",
      "Operation Torch",
    ],
    answer: "Operation Overlord",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which country suffered the highest civilian casualties during World War 2?",
    options: ["Germany", "Soviet Union", "Poland", "Japan"],
    answer: "Soviet Union",
  },
];
